{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Lists in python allows you to store different data types",
      "answers": {
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False",
        "c": "Neither true nor false",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "student_names=('karthik','Raj','Selvi','Mayank','Rupali'), **len(student_names)** will return _______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "4",
        "b": "5",
        "c": "3",
        "d": "Error"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "student_info={\"name\":\"Prasad\",\"Age\":24,\"Hometown\":\"mumbai\",\"Occupation\":\"Engineer\"}, **student_info.keys()** will return _________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "(['name', 'Age', 'Hometown', 'Occupation'])",
        "b": "(['Prasad',24, 'mumbai', 'Engineer'])",
        "c": "Error",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "When you try to access indices which are not present in the list what will happen?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "It will raise an error ",
        "b": "It will raise an IndexErrorException",
        "c": "No output",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "In order to access a range of elements from a tuple, which of the following operator is used?",
      "answers": {
        "a": ":",
        "b": ";",
        "c": "Both (a) and (b)",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "student_names=('karthik','Raj','Selvi','Mayank','Rupali'), **student_names[1:2]** will return?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "('Raj',)",
        "b": "('Raj', 'Selvi')",
        "c": "('Raj', 'Selvi', 'Mayank')",
        "d": "Error"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "student_names=('karthik','Raj','Selvi','Mayank','Rupali'), **student_names[-1:-2]** will return?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "('Rupali',)",
        "b": "()",
        "c": "('Raj', 'Selvi', 'Mayank')",
        "d": "Error"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following datatypes once created does not allows you to modify or change elements?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Set",
        "b": "List",
        "c": "Tuples",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following datatypes once created does not allows you to modify or change elements?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Set",
        "b": "List",
        "c": "Tuples",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "intermediate"
    },
    {
      "question": "numbers=(1,2,2,3,4,5,6,7,7,7), numbers.count(2) will return the output as ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2",
        "b": "3",
        "c": "4",
        "d": "Error"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "student_info={\"name\":\"Prasad\",\"Age\":24,\"Hometown\":\"mumbai\",\"Occupation\":\"Engineer\"}, **student_info.items()** will return?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "([('name', 'Prasad'), ('Age', 24), ('Hometown', 'mumbai'), ('Occupation', 'Engineer')])",
        "b": "(['name', 'Age', 'Hometown', 'Occupation'])",
        "c": "(['Prasad', 24, 'mumbai', 'Engineer'])",
        "d": "Error"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "fruits={'apple','grapes','banana','kiwi','strawberry'}, fruits.index(0) will return _____",
      "answers": {
        "a": "apple",
        "b": "grapes",
        "c": "AttributeError",
        "d": "IndexError"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "advanced"
    },
    {
      "question": "numbers=(1,2,2,3,4,5,6,7,7,7), numbers.index(7) will return the output as?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "2",
        "b": "5",
        "c": "6",
        "d": "7"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "advanced"
    }
  ]
}